Preliminary Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Maury Holland Papers, 1948-1959 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Maury Holland papers 1948-1959 and undated
J. Walter Thompson Company.
1.2 linear feet Extent: 750 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.00711
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In addition, all or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Maury Holland Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a transfer in 1987.
Biographical Note
The J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) was founded in New York in 1864 and is one of the world's oldest and largest advertising firms.
Maury (C. Maurice) Holland was a vaudevillian and Broadway actor (1920s) who worked for Columbia in both silent films and talkie shorts (1930s) and then joined the JWT New York Office's Radio and Television Department in 1936 to direct radio shows for the agency. The Radio/TV Department was responsible for creating and working with radio and television programs to advertise JWT client products. Among other programs, Holland directed Kraft Television Theatre, a live anthology drama series on NBC, from 1948 to the show's cancellation in 1958. He died Nov. 14, 1974 in Greenwich, Conn.
Collection Overview
The J. Walter Thompson Company, Maury Holland papers are dated 1948 to 1959 and include scripts for and copies of outgoing memoranda regarding content and format of television programs and advertisements, as well as budget information for selected shows (1958-1959), all produced by the New York Office's Radio and Television Department. Programs include Bat Masterson, The Jackie Gleason Show, Kraft Television Theatre, Naked City, and The Price Is Right. Actors represented include Milton Berle and Jackie Gleason. Clients include Kraft, Quaker Oats, Rinso Blue, and the Advertising Council. Also includes copies of outgoing correspondence to script writers, NBC, and the JWT Chicago Office. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Subject Headings
Holland, Maury; Berle, Milton; Gleason, Jackie, 1916-1987; Masterson, Bat, 1853-1921; J. Walter Thompson Company; Walter Thompson Company. New York Office; J. Walter Thompson Company. Radio and Television Department; J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office; Kraft Foods Company; Quaker Oats Company; Advertising Council; National Broadcasting Company, Inc.; Jackie Gleason show; Price is right; Naked city; Kraft television theater; Advertising -- History; Advertising executives -- United States; Television advertising -- United States; Television personalities -- United States; Comedians -- United States; Motion picture actors and actresses -- United States; Television plays, American; Television programs -- United States; Scripts; Memoranda; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Contents of Collection
- Accession 2003-0217
  - (Box 1)
    - Bat Masterson, 1958-1959, (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - Gleason AB scripts, 1958 Oct.-Dec., (5 folders) (Box 1)
    - Milton Berle, probably 1958 (Box 1)
    - Mitch Miller, probably 1959 (Box 1)
    - Naked City, probably 1958-1959, (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - The Price Is Right commercials, probably 1958, (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - The Jackie Gleason Show, 1958-1959, (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - The Price Is Right, probably 1958, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - (Box 2)
    - Budberg correspondence, probably 1957-1958 (Box 2)
    - Budgets, 1958 (Box 2)
    - Chicago correspondence, 1958 (Box 2)
    - Chicago correspondence- Naked City, probably 1959 (Box 2)
    - Coldene, probably 1959 (Box 2)
    - East Coast production bills, 1958 (Box 2)
    - Folios, probably 1959 (Box 2)
    - Gleason tape bills, probably 1958 (Box 2)
    - J.P. MC Evoy, probably 1959 (Box 2)
    - Kraft, 1948-1955 and undated (Box 2)
    - Kraft bills, probably 1958 (Box 2)
    - Kraft show, probably 1958 (Box 2)
    - Kraft summer budget, 1958 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous letters, 1958 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous memos, 1958 (Box 2)
    - Most Blessed Woman releases, probably 1958, (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - NBC correspondence, 1958 (Box 2)
    - Quaker Oats commercials, probably 1959 (Box 2)
    - Radio clippings, 1949 (Box 2)
    - Returned scripts, 1958 (Box 2)
    - Rinso Blue, probably 1958 (Box 2)
    - Talent Associates, probably 1958, (2 folders) (Box 2)
      Includes scripts and memoranda regarding Kraft Mystery Theatre.
    - Talent Associates II, 1958 and undated (Box 2)
      Includes scripts and memoranda regarding commericals for the Advertising Council.
    - Teletypes, 1958 (Box 2)